Finding Aid for the Bound Manuscripts Collection LSC.0170
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Bound Manuscripts
  - The History of Gabra Krestos, son of the Emperor Theodosius II (Ethiopia 15th century). **The events of this history seem to be entirely apocryphal., 170/337; Manuscript, on vellum. 102 leaves, with two paintings (fol. 1, 54).
  - Sephardic Ballads, Prayers and Folk-Songs (Rhodes ). **Judeo-Spanish texts written in Hebrew characters., ca. 1750-1900; 170/338; Manuscript, 183 leaves.
  - [Young, Charles B.?] Journal (September 26, 1846-July 3, 1847). **Record of the voyage of the transport Loo Choo from New York to San Francisco carrying units of Colonel Jonathan D. Stevenson's 1st New York Volunteer Regiment to participate in the military conquest of California. Included are descriptions of life aboard the vessel, in San Francisco and at Santa Barbara, where the troops were on garrison duty., 170/339; Manuscript, 52pp.
  - Caldecott, Randolph (1846-1886). A Farmer Went Trotting upon his Grey Mare. With... Original Drawings., ca. 1880; ***170/340; Printed 20 leaves; nine original ink drawings interleaved with eleven printed pages.
  - Lewis, Matthew Gregory (1775-1818). Scrap-Book. **Commonplace book completely filled with fragments, quotations, excerpts and poetry, all by other people., July 1, 1801; Manuscript, 184pp.
  - Views of the Taj Mahal (). Original watercolour paintings. **Finely executed views and details of the Taj Mahal by an unknown artist., ca. 1830; 170/342; 12 leaves.
  - Heber, Reginald, bp of Calcutta (1783-1826). Palestine: a Prize-Poem (Oxford? ). **First published at Oxford, 1807. Ex libris: William Jones, 1803., 170/343; Manuscript, 32 leaves.
  - Heber, Reginald, bishop of Calcutta (1783-1826). A Ballad. Published in Chester., 170/344; Manuscript, 13 leaves, with original wash paintings.
  - Browning, Elizabeth (Barrett) (1806-1861). Answers to Questions. **21 numbered remarks on spiritualism, apparently unpublished., 170/345; Manuscript, 3pp.
  - Blessington, Marguerite (Power) Farmer Gardiner, countess of (1789/1849). The Follies of Fashion, or The Beau Monde of London in 1835. (London ). A satirical sketch, publishing history unknown., ca. 1836; *170/346: 1; Manuscript, 17 leaves.
  - Blessington, Marguerite (Power) Farmer Gardiner, countess of (1789-1849). Lady Blessington and her Court (London: The Hawthorne Press, s.a.). **Includes 4 pencil & tinted drawings of Lady Blessington & Gore House by Alicia Darrington., *170/346: 2; Manuscript, 21 leaves; illustrations.
  - Bible. Manuscripts, Greek. New Testament (Greek ). **The Peckover-Foot Codex. Miniatures of the Evanglists., ca. 1100; 170/347; Manuscript, 254 leaves; illuminated.
  - Bible. Manuscripts. Latin. Old and New Testaments England? s. XIII & #178;). Red and blue throughout with many large elaborately executed capitals. Fols. 355-388: Langton's Interpretationes Hebraicorum Nominum. Cf. Ferrari, pp.65-69., 170/348; Manuscript, on vellum.
  - Extracts (English ). **Commonplace book, Affectionately dedicated to Captain Colquhoun by one of the sincerest of his friends. Beautifully decorated with many fine watercolour drawings., 1808; 170/349; Manuscript, 141pp.
  - Wilson, John (1785-1854). [Notes for the teaching of various courses at the University of Edinburgh (Edinburgh ). **Courses in Greek, logic, and moral philosophy., 1848-1850; 170/350; Manuscript, 2 vol.
  - Schoenbartbuch. [Nuremberg ] **Chronicle of the Nuremberg carnival with finely executed paintings of costumes and floats from 1449 to 1539. Includes coats of arms of the noble families of Nuremberg., ca. 1600.; *170/351; Manuscript, 116 leaves, illustrations.
    See also: Ferrari.
  - Patricii respublicae Nuremberg (Nuremberg ). **Genealogical work on the noble families of Nuremberg with 83 iron engravings by Johann Kaler., ca. 1590; *170/352; Manuscript and printed. 215 leaves.
  - Geschlecht Buch des heiligen Reichstatt Nuremberg (Nuremberg ). **Genealogical book on the noble families of Nuremberg with 81 iron engravings by Johann Kaler of noblemen (handsomely hand-coloured)., ca. 1600; *170/353; Manuscript and printed. 369 leaves.
  - Geschlecht Buch dess heiligen Reichs Stat Nüremberg (Nuremberg ). **Genealogical work on the noble families of Nuremberg with 81 iron engravings of noblemen by Kaler. Handcoloured engraved coat of arms pasted inside front cover., 1610; *170/354; Manuscript and printed, 195 leaves.
  - Der Annder Thaill. Nürembergische Cronica Nuremberg ). **Chronicle listing events from 1530 to 1627. Numerous coats of arms and watercolour paintings of a float and a participant from the 1539 carnival., ca. 1600-1627; *170/355; Manuscript, 357 leaves; illustrations.
  - Pascoe, Charles Eyre, fl. 1870. The Dramatic List: a Record of the Principal Performances of Living Actors and Actresses of the British Stage (London: Hardwicke and Bogue, ). **Interleaved copy. About 100 original letters from various actors and actresses., 1879; 170/356; 2 vol.
  - Hallowell, Maine. Methodist Church. Hallowell class no. 1st. Daniel Wadsworth, leader (Hallowell, Maine, ). **Attendance record book with various facts., 1827-1835; 170/357; Manuscript, 20 leaves.
  - Bonino, Marco. Sketchbook of machines and inventions (N. Italy, s. XVI²; France, s. XVII). **About 400 ink drawings of weight-moving machines, water pumps, clockworks, etc., mostly derived from the works of Francesco di Giorgio Martini and Marianus Jacobus Taccola. Cf. Ferrari, pp.69-70; detailed description, S.A. Bedini in the Collections File., 170/358; Manuscript, 70 leaves.
  - Euripides. The Hecuba of Euripides... for the use of schools and colleges. (London, ). **Annotated with amusing notes and drawings throughout by Henry Charles Brougham, 3rd baron, 1853-1854, whilst a student at Eton., 1852; 170/359
  - Collection of four works on the Chinese language Beijing ). (a) Basilio de Gemona, Franciscan, Table of Chinese characters, 34 leaves; (b) Francisco Varo, Dominican, Spanish-Chinese dictionary, translated into Italian by Ven. Barthelemy Ferrari, Barnabite, 123 leaves; (c) Ferrari, Compendium compiled from the dictionary of Basilio da Gemona, 18 leaves; (d) Ferrari, Chinese-Latin dictionary, 398 leaves Apparently unpublished., ca. 1721/1723; *170/360; Manuscript, on rice paper.
  - Lancaster, Thinne. The Plea between the Advocate and the Antadvocate ... [concerning] Bath and Batholor Knights. **Phillipps manuscript no.8979., ca. 1600; *170/361; Manuscript, 30 leaves.
  - Overbury, Sir Thomas (1581-1613). His observations upon the State of the 17 provinces and of France, and first upon that of the United Province (s.l. s.a.). **First published London,; originally written, 1609. Early 17th century copy. Phillipps Manuscript no.12376., 1626; *170/362; Manuscript, 40pp.
  - Griffin, Francis. [Legal document concerning the debts against the estate, both real and personal, of Francis Griffin. Phillipps Manuscript no.13819., 1694/1695; *170/363; Manuscript, 16pp.
  - System or method observed by the Mexicans and other nations of New Spain in their Division of Time (). **Phillipps Manuscript no.16177. An essay on the Mexican calendar., ca. 1830; *170/364; Manuscript, 19pp.
  - Collection of legal documents (English, ). **Copies of wills and marriage settlements relating to Sir Thomas Plumer, Sir Gregory Page Turner, and Henry Yonge. Phillipps Manuscript no.20133., ca. 1822; *170/365; Manuscript, 5 items.
  - Catholic Church. Liturgy and ritual. Cérémonies pour la reception et la sepulture des religieux de St. Denis (St Denis, Francie, ). **Phillipps Manuscript no.1978. Burial service for the Benedictine monks of the Abbey of St. Denis., 17th century; 170/366; Manuscript, on vellum. 19 leaves.
  - Empereurs, rois et princes regnants du 18e siècle ). Phillipps Manuscript no.10610. Chronology of the states of Europe, 1700-1745, with lists of rules from the late 17th century to 1748. At end is a short chronology of France, 1515/1709., ca. 1750; 170/367; Manuscript, 92 leaves.
  - Instructions politiques, contenant les vertus necessaires a un prince pour bien et heureusement gouvernere les subjects. Du vice et de la vertu. Les peuples sont attaches par une si forte chaine aveq le prince qui les commande (France s. XVII ex.). **Phillipps Manuscript no.13144. An essay on political science., 170/368
  - Sylloge antiquitatum Romanorum cum figuris (Netherlands ). **Phillipps Manuscript no.2445. Copiously illustrated with original drawings and mounted engravings by Ludolf Smids., ca. 1700; 170/369; Manuscript in Latin, 399pp., illustrations.
  - Phosphorus historicus seu chronologicae tabulae, citatis auctoribus illustratae, opera et studio L(udolf) Smids, M.D. Scriptore P(etrus) Vlaming. (Holland ). **Phillipps Manuscript no.2456. A chronology of world history beginning with Adam and Eve, including a chronology of Rome, with a few engravings by Smids of Roman coins mounted on several leaves. Ex libris: E.H.W. Meyerstein., ca. 1700; 170/370; Manuscript, 333 leaves.
  - Proscenium antiquitatis adornatum a Lud. Smids, M.D. ... ornat suppl. Petrus Vlaming. (Holland ). Phillipps Manuscript no.2499. Subject index to the great writings of ancient Rome; a few engravings by Smids of Roman coins mounted on several leaves. Ex libris: E.H.W. Meyerstein., ca. 1700; 170/371; Manuscript, 2 vol.
  - Commonplace Book. (French ). **Phillipps Manuscript no.2500. The first and longest item (22 leaves) is Les enluminures du jeu de la constitution., ca. 1730; 170/372; Manuscript, 47 leaves.
  - Taylor, Joseph (1761 or 1762/1844). Rudiments of Useful Knowledge, conveyed by Symbols and Mathematical Figures; ruled forms; abstracts, & c. (England, ). **Author's own collection., ca. 1810/1825; *170/373; Holograph and printed, 55pp.
  - Spittler, Ludwig Timotheus, Freiherr von (1752-1810). Vorlesung über die Geschichte der weltlichen deutschen Staaten.... (Göttingen 1782). **Phillipps Manuscript no.18545. Course of lectures on the electors of the Holy Roman Empire., 170/374; Manuscript, 553pp.
  - Bouilly, Jean Nicolas (1763-1842). Les jeunes femmes: fesant suite aux contes et avec conseils à ma fille (France ). **First published in Paris, 1820., 1819; *170/375; Manuscript, 127 leaves.
  - An Enquiry into the Situation and Circumstances of Horace's Sabine Villa. Written during Travels through Italy in the years (England, )., 1776-77. ca. 1785; *170/376; Manuscript, 67pp.
  - Hearne, Thomas (1678-1735). Reliquiae Hearnianae: the Remains of Thomas Hearne... being extracts from his Ms. Diaries, collected with a few notes by Philip Bliss... Second edition, enlarged (London: John Russell Smith, 1869). **With notes in ink by William Gaskell Rouse. Ex libris: E.H.W. Meyerstein., 170/377; 3 vol.
  - Bird Paintings Collection (England? )., ca. 1830; *170/378; 72 items. Original watercolour paintings.
  - L., R. Of the soule of the man Adam, in the earthly or blouddy being; and of the state thereof in the deified being: of his fall and restauration: a short declaration to those that can comprehend understtanding Parables for Pastime. (English, )., ca. 1700; 170/379; Manuscript, 51 leaves.
  - [Reports of Venetian Ambassadors from Spain, Rome, and France, various places (1558-1623). **Relazione ... Michel Soriano ritornato ambasciatore da Filippo Re di Spagna l'anno 1560; Rel. ... Bernardo Navagero ... Tornando di Roma ambasciatore a Papa Paolo IV l'anno 1558; Rel. ... Giovanni Correro Tornato ambasciatore dal Re di Francia l'anno 1570; Conclave di Papa Gregorio XIIII ... l'anno 1590; Prerogative e doveri del Nunzio di Napoli; Conclave per l'elezione di Urbano VIII Barberini l'anno 1623. The first 3 reports are published., *170/380; Manuscript, 186 leaves.
    See also: Ferrari, p.71.
  - The Practice of the Court of Chancery in the Grand Sessions for the Several Countys of Glamorgan, Brecon & Radnor (England, ). **A commonplace book containing various legal definitions and explanations., ca. 1750-1790; 170/381
  - Jacobus de Voragine. Sermones de tempore, with additions (Italy s. XIV²). **Bound in wooden boards., 170/382; Manuscript, 389 leaves.
    See also: Ferrari, pp.72-75.
  - Legal Broadsides (Mexico, printed by Pedro Ocharte, )., ca. 1560; *170/383; Printed legal forms, filled in by hand.
  - [Granjux, Giovanni Giuseppe?] Apparecchi e feste della citta di Fossano per l'arrivo del suo nuovo e sospirato Vesco Monsignore Luigi Fransoni, Patrizio Genovese. (Fossano, Italy 1821). **Fransoni (1789-1862) was appointed Bishop in This poem describes his procession and welcome by the town., 170/384; Manuscript, 193 leaves.
  - Marolles, Michel de (1600-1681). Catalogue de livres d'estampes & de figures en taille-douche. Avec un dénombrement des pièces qui y sont continuës. Fait à Paris en l'année 1672 (Paris? ). **Manuscript copy, made about 1825, of the book published in 1672. It is a continuation of Marolles's work of 1666., ca. 1825; 170/385; Manuscript, 86pp.
  - Collection of Church Music, some traditional, some by individuals. (England, ). **Possibly compiled by W.H. Sinnett. Missing first leaf. Many of the hymns are Welsh., ca. 1850; 170/386; Manuscript, 60 leaves.
  - Collection of Songs and Music (England ). **Includes 2 songs by Shakespeare. Ex libris: Isaac Foot., 18th century; 170/387; Manuscript, 25 leaves.
  - Frescobaldi, Girolamo (1583-1643). Fiori musicali di diverse compositioni toccate, kyrie, canzoni, capricci, ricercari in partitura a quatro utili per sonatori autore Girolamo Frescobaldi. Organista di San Pietro di Roma. (Venice: Alessandro Vicenti, ). (Germany?). **Apparently this is a manuscript copy made from the work published at Venice in, 1635 1635.; 170/388; Manuscript, 71pp.
  - Arie e duetti di diversi autori replicati (Italy s.a.). **Compositions for solo voice and accompaniment by Rinaldo di Capua, Leonardo Vinci, Nicola Antonio Porpora, and Leonardo Leo., 170/389; Manuscript, 95 leaves.
  - Pallavicini, Carlo (1630-1688). La Gierusaleme liberata (Italy). **An opera. Ex libris: Charles Montagu, Earl of Manchester (1660?-1722)., 170/390; Manuscript, 133 leaves.
  - Bononcini, Giovanni Battista (1670-1755?). Il Ciro arie del Bononcini (Italy s.a.). **Arias from Bononcini's opera Ciro ovvero Odio ed amore, produced in, 1721.; 170/391; Manuscript, 58 leaves.
  - [Sarri, Domenico (1679-1744).] Gli amanti generosi. **Act III only. Music for an opera, Teatro dei Fiorentini, Naples, May 15, 1735.; 170/392; Manuscript, 62 leaves.
  - Accounts of Three Trials (England, ). **Divorce of Lady Frances Howard and the Earl of Essex, 1613; Trial of Richard Weston et al. for murdering Sir Thomas Overbury, 1615; Trial of Lord Mervin Touchet, Earl of Castlehaven, for rape and sodomy, 1631. Phillipps Manuscript no.21547., ca. 1650; *170/393; Manuscript, 253pp.
  - High Life. A Novel (England, ). **Publishing history unknown: possibly published under another title. A novel called High Life was published in 1827, but it is apparently a different work., ca. 1815; 170/394; Manuscript.
  - Bennett, Raphael Fabian (1895-1957). The Shelter of the Cloth (Los Angeles, ). **An unpublished novel about Mexico in the time of Benito Juarez. The author was the actor Ray Bennett., ca. 1950; Corrected Typescript, 395 leaves.
  - Grolig, Moriz (b. 1873). Bibliography of Toten-Gespräche or Dialogues of the Dead, 1495-1792. (Venice )., ca. 1900-1950; 170/396: 1-3; Manuscript, 3 vol.
  - Sala, George Augustus Henry (1828-1895). The Real Woman in White. (A Story told without Disparagement to Mr. Wilkie Collins). (England, ). **Publishing history unknown., ca. 1873; 170/397; Manuscript, 19 leaves.
  - Kingsley, Henry (1830-1876). The Hillyars and the Burtons: a Story of Two Families (England, ). **Part of a novel, in 3 vol., published in 1865 by Macmillan., ca. 1865; *170/398; 29 leaves only.
  - Hawkins, Sir Anthony Hope (1863-1933). The Dolly Dialogues by Anthony Hope, with 18 illustrations by Howard Chandler Christy (New York ). **Tipped in are two letters from Hawkins to Robert Howard Russell, the publisher,, and a letter from Christy to Russell., 1901 October 10, 1899 and April 9, 1901; 170/399
  - Petrus Ximenes, frater. Clara & perutilisque explanatio in logam parvam Aristotelis (Spain ). **A treatise on Duns Scotus' work on Aristotle. On the first three leaves are ink and watercolour decorations., 1744; 170/400; Manuscript, 224 leaves.
  - Ville-Toustain, (197) de. Tragedie de la naissance, ou création du monde (France s.a.). **Manuscript copy by F.F. Dyot of the printed book, apparently published in the 17th century., 170/401; Manuscript, 32pp.
  - Howe, Solomon (1760-1835). Hymns and tunes, interspersed with accounts, inventories, family records, and essays on music (Massachusetts )]. **Apparently Solomon Howe's master-copy in which he noted everything he wrote., ca. 1805-1822; 170/402; Manuscript, 112pp.
  - Manuscript leaves. **An extensive collection of manuscript leaves, mostly in Latin (9th-16th centuries). For the Latin texts., ***170/403; Manuscript, ca. 125 leaves in 2 boxes.
    See also: Ferrari, pp.209-362.
  - Forster, John, 1812-1876. The Life of Charles Dickens (London, ). **Extra-illustrated copy by William Miller, Shoreditch, England, with about 540 original letters and about 2000 pictures and ephemera, all relating to persons and places in the biography. A list of letters is in the collections file., 1872-1874; *170/404; 3 vol. in 12.
  - Woodward, Robert William. An easy Introduction to Reading and Spelling (London, )., 1829; 170/405; Manuscript, 48pp.
  - Palmotta, Giacomo, cavliere. Descrizione del terremoto di Ragusa, avvenuto il giorno 6 Aprile 1667, fatta in versi Illirici dal rinomato Cavaliere Giacomo Palmottz Raguseo, e tradotta in Italiano volgare dal Signor Marino Slatarichi Raguseo, e copiata a Ragusa il 7 Marzo 1819 da Marco Marinovich (Ragusa [Dubrovnik] ). Apparently unpublished., 170/406; Manuscript, 101 leaves.
  - Paer, Fernando, 1771-1839. La Camilla [o il Sotterraneo] ... in Roma dell'archivico di Derosi concetti, Posto al Teatro Valle in Via Canestrari, no.8 (Italy ). **An opera in three acts, includes music and words., ca. 1800; 170/407; Manuscript, music. 2 vol.
  - Newton, William, vicar of Gillingham, Dorset. A vindication of the Reverend Dr. White Kennett, Dean of Peterborough, as to his writings, & conduct of his Life: on Occasion of several Late Jacobite Libels against him (England ). **This biography, with substantial changes and omissions, was published in London in 1730 (cf. Special Collections BX 5199 K3N4)., 1717; *170/408; Manuscript, 335 leaves.
  - Bannatyne Club, Edinburgh. Ephemera (Edinburgh ). **Includes lists of rules, members, candidates, club publications, invitations, notices, etc., ca. 1822-1833; 170/409; Manuscript and printed. 3 vol.
  - Bégon, Michel, 1638-1710. Five letters concerning the foreign relations between France and Morocco, **Two of the letters are from Mulai Isma'il, 3rd sultan of Morocco, on a proposal of marriage between the sultan and a daughter of Louis XIV; one letter is from Louis XIV., ca. 1700.; *170/410; Manuscript, 22pp. (copy).
  - Mechanical Engineering. Two courses: on the theoretical construction of machines, and on steam engines., ca. 1850; *170/411; Manuscript, German; illustrated with many skillful ink drawings.
  - The Amateur: a Journal of General Literature; Critical, Historical, Philosophical, Comical, Tragical, Political, Poetical, & Social; with illustrations by eminent artists (London, ). **Edited by George & J.S. Cavell., 1847-1848; 170/412; Manuscript, 292pp.
  - Gerard, John(?), translator. Desiderius, or the Readie Way to the Loue of God. Written in dialogue wise, under learned and pleasaunt allegories. First put forth in the Spanish Tonge; and after translated into Latin: and nowe lately into Englishe for the behoof of the deuout of our nation. **Apparently unpublished translation from the Spanish version by Miguel Comalada., ca. 1595; 170/413; Manuscript, 84 leaves.
  - Recueil de quantité de pieces galantes. Tant en contes qu'en epigrammes ()., 1710; 170/414; Manuscript, 496+ leaves. **Frontispiece painted in colour on vellum.
  - R., A. Female head dresses from y[e] antique. Original water-colour drawings of Greek coins, all showing women's heads, made from the coin collection of Thomas Burgon., 1833; 170/415; Manuscript, 20 leaves.
  - [Courtin, called Maur, novice.] Copie d'une lettre écrite de l'Abbaye de la Trappe a Madame de Ligny, Chanoinesse Desainte Marie a Metz (France ). **Account of the Abbey of Notre Dame de la Trappe., November 1706; 170/416; Manuscript, 39 leaves.
  - Tennyson, Alfred, baron (1809-1892). Poems (London, ). Extra-illustrated edition with 57 pen and ink drawings by Robert Spencer Borland for his mother., 1848; 170/417
  - Havas, Charles Louis (1783-1858). Letters to Havas from J.P. de Roure and H.G.W. (London, ). **Approximately 220 letters, written in French. Bound by Doll., 1810/1813; 170/418; Manuscript, 2 vol.
  - Lyra apostolica, Second edition. (London, )., 1837; 170/419; **Interleaved copy withnotes by Charles Arthur Griffith, Moberley, and Pusey.
  - France. Bibliothèque nationale. Cabinet des titres. Cata-logue de la collection des pièces originales. 3061 vol. (Paris, ). **Listed alphabetically., 1896; *170/420; Manuscript, 2 vol.
  - Lilford, Thomas Littleton Powys, 4th baron (1833-1896). Catalogue of the books in the study at Lilford Hall (Oundle, Peterborough, ). **Arranged alphabetically by author; many of the books are on ornithology., 1879; 170/421; Manuscript, 139 leaves.
    See also: 170/423 and 170/437.
  - Williamson, George Charles (1858-1942). Scrapbook devoted to Angelica Kauffmann, the painter., ca. 1920-1925; *170/422; **Numerous photographs of her paintings, clippings and other ephemera. 55 leaves.
  - Lilford, Thomas Littleton Powys, 3rd baron (1801-1861). Catalogue of the books in the study at Lilford Hall (Oundle, Peterborough, )., 1840-1845; 170/423; Manuscript, 139 leaves. **Arranged alphabetically by author
    See also: 170/421 and 170/437.
  - Ashley, William Thomas B. A Catalogue of the Library (ca. 1865-1875). **The library was auctioned by Sotheby's on March 20, 1876., 170/424; Manuscript, 129 leaves.
  - Pettre, Hon. Edmund George. An Historical Description of the Steam Engine, from its first invention up to the present time. Part 1 (Birmingham, )., 1844; 170/425; Manuscript, 48 leaves; illustrations.
  - Murasaki shikibu (b. 978). Genji utakagami (Japan, ). **Collection of poems taken from The Tale of Genji. Manuscript copied by Masayuki Kuboshima., January 1818; 170/426; Manuscript, 107 leaves.
  - Ashton, John (b. 1834). Florizel's folly (London, ). **Extra illustrated copy with a large number of pictures of persons and places mentioned in the book. Anecdotes of the life of George IV., 1899; 170/427
  - Caricatures. Volumes 3 and 4 only (English, ). **These clever and well executed caricatures have been attributed to Mark Lemon. vol.3 has 36 caricatures; vol.4 has 88., ca. 1835/1840; 170/428; 2 vol.
  - Dickenson, Samuel, of Blymhill, Staffordshire. Journals. **Journal of voyage to Goree in Africa; Journal Mediterranean, Gibraltar; Journal from London to Marseilles; Journal from Marseilles to Genoa; Journal from Florence to Rome and Journies [sic] in Wales; tropical trees, fruits, grains; The Campidoglio a Roma., 1758-1798; 170/429; Manuscript, 8 vol.
  - Cervantes, Miguel. Illustrations by various artists for Don Quixote (Madrid, )., 1780; *170/430; **77 leaves. Original engravings mounted on sheets.
  - Dizionario delle Venete famiglie patrizie (Venice, ). **Arranged alphabetically by family. Includes about 700 painted coats-of-arms. Formerly owned by Sir Henry Austen Layard., ca. 1650; 170/431; Manuscript, 147 leaves.